<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NobenLog</title>
    <link>https://noben.org/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on NobenLog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 16:42:12 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noben.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configure Visual Studio Code on macOS to get breakpoints on Apple Silicon (M1/M2)</title>
      <link>https://noben.org/blog/posts/configure-vscode-debug-clang-breakpoints-apple-silicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 16:42:12 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noben.org/blog/posts/configure-vscode-debug-clang-breakpoints-apple-silicon/</guid>
      <description>Breakpoints on Apple Silicon As an update to my previous post, when I upgraded to Apple Silicon ARM based laptops and computer (M1/M2), I learnt the hard way that debugging via gdb is no more.
There is thankfully, now, an alternative. Here are the steps.
Install CodeLLDB in VSCode The key is to use lldb instead of gdb, which comes with XCode (you might need to install xcode tools first).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change LSP settings in BBEdit for Intelliphense</title>
      <link>https://noben.org/blog/posts/bbedit-lsp-intelliphense-settings-braces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 21:05:49 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noben.org/blog/posts/bbedit-lsp-intelliphense-settings-braces/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently having moved to BBEdit, one thing that drove me crazy was the formatting using intelliphense (PHP) would automatically use PSR12 (default) where it puts the curly brace on a new line.
Say what you will about code style and all but I wanted K&amp;amp;R.
In VSCode this is trivial, edit the config, add a line and done. In BBEdit, not so quick!
The setup Once you have intelliphense set up properly in BBEdit - see this page and search for &amp;ldquo;php&amp;rdquo;: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Visual Studio Code with clangd, clang for builds, to use gdb for debugging and makefile</title>
      <link>https://noben.org/blog/posts/configure-vscode-clang-makefile-build-launch-breakpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 22:14:57 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noben.org/blog/posts/configure-vscode-clang-makefile-build-launch-breakpoints/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Running C/C++ on macOS with VSCode, clang and gdb, can be quite interesting (challenging) to set up.
I&amp;rsquo;m no expert, but this is how I did it and it might help you. I certainly document it for my own benefit as well.
VSCode + clangd Once VSCode is installed, install clangd as a plugin. This is the language server used in the backend of VSCode which will give you auto completion and &amp;ldquo;click through&amp;rdquo; navigation between header files and code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfectly hard-boiled eggs via steaming method on induction cooktops</title>
      <link>https://noben.org/blog/posts/perfect-hard-boiled-eggs-via-steaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 09:28:10 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noben.org/blog/posts/perfect-hard-boiled-eggs-via-steaming/</guid>
      <description>Introduction After struggling with making easy-to-peal and perfectly cooked eggs every time, I found a really good method I&amp;rsquo;d like to document.
The main issue is the induction cooktops, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to make eggs via boiling that will be consistent every time.
I found this steaming technique and it works absolute wonders. I&amp;rsquo;ve made quite a lot of eggs, of various sizes, age, and it&amp;rsquo;s been great consistently on an electric cooktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Mousewheel Speed on Debian/Linux Mint incl. Cinammon etc.</title>
      <link>https://noben.org/blog/posts/configure-mousewheel-speed-debian-mint-cinammon-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 21:47:27 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noben.org/blog/posts/configure-mousewheel-speed-debian-mint-cinammon-etc/</guid>
      <description>The following fixes the slow mousewheel on debian/mint using Cinammon / GTK3. install a package called imwheel and use a script that generates a small UI to tweak the setting. personal settings will be saved in ~/.imwheelrc.
sudo apt install imwheel touch ~/mousewheel.sh # edit and paste the mousewheel.sh chmod +x ~/mousewheel.sh ~/mousewheel.sh # opens a GTK UI, I found the value 4-5 to be about right Contents of mousewheel.sh #!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Slack on Debian Bullseye</title>
      <link>https://noben.org/blog/posts/install-slack-debian-bullseye/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 21:36:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noben.org/blog/posts/install-slack-debian-bullseye/</guid>
      <description>So you want to install slack&amp;hellip; Go to https://slack.com and get their latest .deb install file for Linux
if you attempt to install it as, you should get some missing requirements warning and it bails.
sudo apt install &amp;lt;slack.deb&amp;gt;
failed: requirements missing
Sadly some required packages don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be up to date! The simplest way is to install the required packages from the repository manually until all requirements are there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>